Feng Sir.
冯哥
I have always distrusted Chen Hao.
我一直都不放心陈浩
He looks obedient,
看着低眉顺眼的
but you can't teach an old dog new tricks.
其实狗改不了吃屎
He's been in cahoots with Xiang Yuansheng
早就跟华桢勾结在一起
since their time at the Fourth Station.
在四所的时候
They've had it in for me for quite some time.
两个人就跟我过不去
Are you sure you didn't see
你确定你没看清楚
who got shot?
中枪的人是谁
I didn't.
确实没有看见
Luo Minmin was unconscious.
骆珉敏已经晕了
It must be either Chen Hao or Hua Zhen.
不是陈浩就是华桢
What if
那如果是华桢
it was Hua Zhen?
该怎么办呢
He's the son
他可是
of the Undersecretary of the Ministry of Military Affairs.
军政部次长的儿子呀
If he's the one injured...
这他要是把人
Now you're wiser.
你现在聪明了
Do I need you to tell me that?
用得着你告诉我
Why don't you dispose
弄死田冬宝
Tian Dongbao's body?
也不知道马上处理
What the hell use are you to me?
我要你有什么用
My fault, Feng Sir. My mistake.
我错了 冯哥 我错了
Now that they know,
现在他们知道了
The thing will come to light.
事情肯定压不住
I need to find someone
我得找个人
to pin the murder charge on.
顶替凶手的罪名
So, you want to
那你是想
frame one of those three?
栽到他们三个人头上
That's the easiest solution.
这样最省事儿
We need a perpetrator for the case.
案子需要一个凶手
Issuing a warrant
通缉令发出去
will keep them tied up.
还能困住他们
But we can't issue it against Hua Zhen.
但是不能通缉华桢
His family would give me trouble.
他家人会找我麻烦
It has to be Chen Hao.
只能是陈浩
Arrange an eyewitness.
我们安排个目击证人
Understood.
好
I'll put San on that,
我马上交给老三
and he will be an eyewitness.
让他当这目击证人
And, Feng Sir,
对了冯哥
what evidence should we prepare?
这证据需要准备什么呢
Anything will do.
随便
In this case,
现在这个案子
what I say happened,
我说怎么回事儿
happened.
就是怎么回事儿
The only person
唯一能把这个事儿
who could blow this wide open
捅出去的
is Hua Zhen.
就是华桢
What do we do then?
那怎么办呢
Find him and that woman,
找到他跟那个女的
and terminate both.
就干掉
Got it.
好
Feng Sir,
科长
this is the forensic report
这是三洋水产公司
for the deceased from San Yang Fisheries.
那名死者的法医报告
The body shows multiple external injuries
身上多处是外伤
and signs of being beaten before death,
生前被殴打过
but the cause of death was hypothermia.
死因是冻死的
Hypothermia?
冻死的
Why did I receive
那为什么我今天早上
a call this morning
会接到举报电话
reporting a shooting?
说是枪杀
A shooting?
枪杀
That's...
这
Moreover, the caller claimed
而且人家还举报
the murderer
凶手就是
was one of our own,
我们的身边人
Chen Hao!
陈浩
How could it be Chen Hao?
这怎么可能是陈浩
He claimed to have witnessed
而且人家亲眼看见了
the entire murder process!
整个杀人过程
Why would he?
他为什么要杀啊
Why don't you investigate?
要不你来查
Where is Chen Hao now?
陈浩人呢
He hasn't shown up this morning.
他早上就没来
Killed someone and now he's too scared to show up.
杀了人 当然不敢来了
Issue a warrant for his arrest.
下通缉令吧
Yes Sir.
是
Inspector Shi,
石督察
this is a request for assistance
这是华界公安局
in a murder case from the Public Security Bureau,
发来的协助通缉申请
sent to us for action.
是一桩凶杀案
The Director instructed me
总监让我把这一份
to hand it to you
交给您
for distribution to the patrol houses.
下发巡捕房
When was this received?
这什么时候发来的
Just now.
刚刚
They've also requested
他们还申请了
permission for police to enter
让华界的警察
the French Concession to apprehend the suspect,
来法租界搜捕
as the fugitive
因为凶手本身
is a police officer
就是一个警察
and considered dangerous.
比较危险
The Director has already approved it.
总监已经批准了
Alright, I got it.
好 我知道了
I'll distribute it to the patrol houses shortly.
一会儿我下发巡捕房
Yes, madam.
是
Captain has a fever.
队长发烧了
His wound is infected.
他的伤口发炎了
Where is your watch?
你的手表呢
I sold it.
卖了
We need to go into town.
我们得进趟城
I had the pharmacist
我托了药店老板
to buy some sulfanilamide powder.
买磺胺粉
We need it to fight the infection.
他现在需要立马消炎
Newspapers!
卖报
Newspapers for sale!
卖报了
That's Feng Guangyun.
是冯广云
Feng Sir.
科长
We can't go to that pharmacy now.
这家药店我们去不了了
What do we do?
怎么办
Where else can we go?
现在还能去哪儿
Let's try the medical facility at Jiangnan Shipyard.
去造船所的附属医院
Although I'm
虽然我现在
off duty now,
不在任务期间
it's our only option.
但也只能试试了
Feng Sir,
科长
he was spotted buying sulfanilamide powder
他去黑市买磺胺粉
in the black market.
被我们的人看见了
Someone traded this
有人拿这个
for sulfanilamide powder?
跟你换磺胺粉
Yes.
是
The watch seemed quite valuable,
我看这表确实挺值钱
so I agreed.
我就答应了
Was it this person?
是这个人吗
No.
不是
Came alone?
一个人来的
Yes,
对
a young man,
一个人
in his twenties,
二十多岁的一个小伙
decent-looking.
模样还挺周正的
What else did he buy from you?
他还跟你买了什么
Frostbite medicine, alcohol,
冻伤药 酒精
gauze, bandages,
纱布 绷带
all for disinfection purposes.
都是消毒用的东西
Uh,
对了
and he also
他还跟我
traded for a blanket
要了一张毛毯
and some food.
和一些吃的
Chen Hao was the one
那天在水产公司
shot at San Yang Fisheries.
中枪的是陈浩
Immediately notify all cooperating departments
马上通知各协查部门
and checkpoint police
还有关卡的巡警
to be on the lookout
让他们注意
for a suspect with a gunshot wound.
嫌疑犯身上有枪伤
Yes Sir.
是
Follow me.
跟着我
Sir, please show me your ID.
你好 请出示证件
Second Lieutenant,
少尉
who's in the back seat?
车后座是谁
He's my friend.
我的朋友
Please wait a moment.
请稍等
Don't move!
别动
Stop right there!
停下
No?
没有
No, I don't.
真没有
You,
你
do you have a sister?
你是不是有个姐姐
Yes.
是啊
Is your sister named Luo Minmin?
你姐姐是不是叫骆珉敏
Was she with the Fourth Station?
她是不是四所的
Listen,
我告诉你啊
don't try to deceive me.
你不要蒙我
Your sister
你姐姐
is connected to this person.
跟这个人是有关联的
If you don't
如果你们
confess,
不老实交代的话
we can shut down your shop
封了你的店
and arrest you
抓你们
for prison, believe it or not?
吃牢饭信不信
They've actually traced it here.
他们竟然查到这儿了
Feng Guangyun knows
冯广云知道
we need
我们现在需要
supplies and medicine,
各种补给和药
anticipating we'd come to your place.
猜到我们会来你家
He's trying
他就是想把
to block every way
我们所有求救的路
we might seek help.
都给堵死
I haven't seen him.
真没见过
What crime did he commit?
他犯了什么罪
What crime?
犯了什么罪
He's connected
他跟一起谋杀案
to a murder case.
是有关系的
If you're worried,
如果担心
I can try to get you home
等天黑了我再想办法
after dark.
送你回一趟家
It's okay.
没关系
Let's go.
我们走吧
Have you seen this man?
你们有没有见过这个人
Is that the inspector
这是不是法租界
from the French Concession?
那个督察员哪
Seems like her.
好像是
Quick, notify Mr. Wei!
快通知魏先生
Later,
那一会儿
we need to take measurements again...
要重新量个尺寸
Mrs. Ji.
季太太
Please have a seat.
您先坐一下
Okay.
好
My suit
我这衣服
need a bit of adjustment.
还需要再动一动
Can you check it for me?
你帮我看一下吧
Right this way, please.
里面请
What's the rush?
这么急
Is something wrong?
是出什么事儿了吗
Chen Hao is wanted.
陈浩被通缉了
I just received a request for assistance
我刚收到十六铺分局
in apprehension from Shiliupu Police Station,
发来的协查通缉申请
stating the suspect
上面写的是
has a gunshot wound.
嫌疑人有枪伤
He's been shot.
他中枪了
What's he wanted for?
什么原因被通缉的
Murder,
谋杀
just like Mr. Peng.
和彭记者一样
It's Feng Guangyun's
这是冯广云
usual tactic.
最惯用的手段
Have you tried contacting Chen Hao?
你有试着联系陈浩吗
Can't reach him.
联系不到
He didn't show up
他昨天晚上
for the French class last night,
就没有来法语班上课
and the last time I saw him
我最后一次见他
he was going
是交代他
to continue investigating
把军需品走私案
the military supplies smuggling case.
接着往下查
He mentioned that Xiang Yuansheng would join him.
他说向远生要一起
It seems something unexpected
估计在查的时候
happened during their investigation.
出了什么意外的状况
What about Xiang Yuansheng,
那向远生呢
can you reach him?
能联系到吗
No contact with him either.
也联系不到
Chen Hao managed to escape despite being shot
陈浩中枪能够脱身
I guess, because he was
说明他是跟向远生
with Xiang Yuansheng.
在一起的
From the details of the warrant,
而且从通缉的内容来看
it seems Chen Hao's identity
陈浩的身份
hasn't been compromised.
应该没有被暴露
Otherwise, Feng Guangyun could have
不然冯广云完全可以
arrested him under the pretext of
以逮捕共产党的名义
apprehending a communist,
逮捕他
instead of fabricating
而不是捏造一个
a murder charge.
谋杀的罪名
If Chen Hao's identity is still secure,
陈浩的身份没有暴露
then the investigation into the smuggling case
那调查走私案
is just between him
就是他和冯广云
and Feng Guangyun,
之间的事情
which means there's still a chance.
就还有一线生机
But that's just me
可是这都只是
being optimistic.
我乐观的估计
Junyu,
珺昱
leave the clothes with me.
衣服先放在我这儿
Remember,
你要记住
you came here
你这次来找我
because the sleeves of this garment
是因为这件衣服
are too large,
袖子太大
and you needed a tailor for the adjustment.
你是来找我改袖子的
What you need to do now
你现在要做的
is go straight back to the Council
就是马上回公董局
and protect yourself,
保护好自己
as you are likely the only one
因为你是唯一一个
they might turn to for help,
他们有可能求助的人
and possibly
也是他们
their last resort.
最后的出路
Where's the owner?
老板呢
She seems to be...
老板好像在
Anyone here?
有人吗
Owner!
老板
Ms. Shi, what do you think of it?
石小姐 感觉怎么样
I think the sleeves
我觉得袖子
are still a bit too large.
还是大了一点
Could you adjust them again?
还是再改改吧
Ms. Shi?
石小姐
Inspector Shi!
石督察员
Long time no see.
好久不见啊
You are?
您是
It's Daiqing.
我岱擎啊
Wei Daiqing,
魏岱擎
the former head of the investigation team
就是淞沪警备司令部
at the Shanghai Garrison Command.
侦查队队长
I accompanied you
上次陪您
to buy flowers last time.
买过花
Captain Wei, sorry,
魏队长 不好意思
I didn't recognize you.
刚刚没有认出你来
It's okay.
没关系
I'm no longer the head
我现在已经不是
of the investigation team.
侦查队队长了
I've left the Shanghai Garrison Command.
我离开警备司令部了
So, what brings Mr. Wei here today?
那魏先生今天是来
Well,
我
just wandering around.
随便逛逛
Didn't expect
没想到这么巧
to bump into you here, Ms. Shi.
在这儿碰到石小姐您了
You might be disappointed then.
那可能要让你失望了
Mrs. Ji
季太太这里啊
only makes women's clothing.
只做女装
I...
我
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
is this gentleman a friend of yours?
这位是您的朋友
Yes.
是
No,
不是
just had some
只是公务上
official interactions.
有些往来
Ms. Shi is frequent client.
石小姐熟悉我的店
I usually
我平常
don't make men's clothing.
确实不大做男装
However, I do know a tailor
不过我倒是认识一个
who is very skilled in men's apparel.
做男装手艺很好的师傅
I could refer him to you.
可以推荐给先生
No rush.
不着急
Actually, I was
其实今天啊
just strolling today.
我就是随便逛逛
Didn't expect
没想到
to see her here.
在您这儿碰见她了
Mrs. Ji, please help me
季太太那麻烦你
adjust the sleeves.
帮我改一下袖子
I'll be leaving now.
我就先走了
I'll let you know when it's done.
我改好了 你再来
Okay.
好
Enjoy your browsing. I'll be leaving now.
您慢慢逛 我先走了
I won't linger either.
我也不瞎逛了
I should get going.
我也该走了
Take care.
慢走
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
are you heading back to the Council?
您是回公董局吗
Yes.
是
Great.
太好了
I drove here.
顺路的
My car is
我开车来的
just down the street.
车就停在那头
I can give you a ride.
我送您
Thank you for that.
那就谢谢了
This way.
请
The tailor shop
刚才那个裁缝铺
is quite a distance
离公董局
from the Council,
距离可不近
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
It's not that far,
也不算远
just a half-hour walk.
走路也就半个小时吧
You often go there, Ms. Shi?
石小姐经常去啊
I'll pick up a garment in two days,
过两天还会再去取衣服
and I sometimes
平时没事
check out new fabrics.
也会去看看新的布料
I will never have too many clothes.
反正我永远不嫌衣服多
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
I hear women
我听说你们女人
prefer to shop in groups.
逛街总喜欢成群结队的
How come you're alone?
你怎么一个人呢
Many French female staff at the Council
公董局好些法国女职员
like to have their clothes made there.
都喜欢在这儿做衣服
They're particularly interested in cheongsams.
她们对旗袍特别感兴趣
I came to know about it
我也是听她们推荐
through their recommendations.
才来的
Mr. Wei,
魏先生
you're not offering me a ride
你让我坐你的顺风车
just to investigate something about me, are you?
不是要调查我什么吧
I wouldn't dare.
我哪里敢
Ms. Shi, you may not know,
石小姐 你不知道吧
but I'm no longer
我早就不在
working at the investigation team.
侦查队里干了
You sure don't sound like it.
听你说话口气可真不像
My apologies.
惭愧 惭愧
Probably an old habit
可能是因为
of mine,
以前的臭毛病
or perhaps
也可能是因为
it's Ms. Shi's charm,
石小姐魅力非凡
making me babble.
魏某人没话找话
To be honest, Ms. Shi,
实不相瞒 石小姐
I've secured a job within your French Concession.
我就在你们法租界
I've got another job
谋了一份差事
and quitted the tough job
早就不干侦查队
in the investigation team any more.
那些肮脏活了
Where did you work?
哪家公司高就啊
AG Brewery.
安琪啤酒公司
I work as a buyer.
当一个采购员
The welfare of the company
那这家公司的待遇
is really nice.
可真不错
On joining the company,
刚去没多久
they bought a car for you.
就给你配辆车子
If I didn't work in the Council
以后我要不在公董局了
I should join the company, too.
也应该去你这家公司
You must be kidding.
那绝不能够
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
It's a waste of talent.
太屈才了
You
您
work in such a high position
在公董局
in the Council.
混下这么重要的职位
It's an amazing achievement
一个华人
for a Chinese
还是一个女人
and a female.
多不容易
Your leader
你们上司
wouldn't let you go.
肯定不会放你走
I can work in the Council
我也不完全是
not solely because of
靠自己的本事
my talents.
才进入公董局的
My parents have a longstanding friendship
我父母和法伯尔总监
with Director Faber's family,
家里是世交
which is why
所以我才可以
I was able to firmly secure
稳稳地坐上
the position of Inspector.
督察员这个位置
Generally,
平时一般人
people wouldn't dare to bother me.
也不敢来找我的麻烦
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
how well
季太太跟您
do you know Mrs. Ji?
到底熟不熟呀
Very well.
熟悉
What's wrong?
怎么了
Wonderful.
太好了
My mother's birthday is coming up
过几天啊
a few days later.
我妈生日
and I would really love to
我还真想
get her a cheongsam.
给她老人家订一套旗袍
I'll need to
到时候
impose on Mrs. Ji's expertise.
肯定要麻烦到季太太
Mr. Wei,
魏先生
Mrs. Ji's workmanship
你放心去
surely
季太太的手艺
won't let you down.
是不会让你失望的
Thank you.
谢谢
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
I realize
刚在路上
I may have been quite thoughtless
我说话有点儿不太注意
with my words on the road earlier,
可能有一些话
which might have seemed rather forward.
让您觉得很冒昧
Well,
这样
I apologize for it.
我在这儿向您道个歉
When might you have some free time
您哪天有时间啊
Ms. Shi?
石小姐
I would be honored
您赏光
if you would let me
魏某人请您
buy you a beer.
喝啤酒
Thank you for the ride.
谢谢你的顺风车
Did anyone call me
我离开这段时间
when I've been gone?
我办公室有来电话吗
No calls, inspector.
没有 石督察
Noted, thank you.
好 我知道了
I've been driving it for the last two days,
这两天一直开
which may have caused overheated water tank.
应该是水箱过热
We have no choice but to wait it out.
只好等会儿了
Captain,
队长
how do you feel?
你醒了
we didn't find
我们
a proper hospital.
没有找到合适的医院
We'll take you
等到天亮了
as soon as
我们就带你
it gets light.
带你去
Today,
我今天听见
I heard about the wanted order.
通缉令的事了
We can't go to hospitals or clinics
医院和诊所
for the time being.
暂时去不了了
And we can't stay in hotels or inns either.
饭店和客栈也不能住
Once the car is fixed,
一会儿等车好了
we'll have to return to
我们还是得回到
where we were yesterday.
昨天那个地方
I'll figure this out tomorrow.
明天我再想想办法
If we can't buy sulfanilamide in the clinic,
药店没有磺胺粉
I'll go to the black market.
我就去黑市买
There is always a way.
总会有办法的
What did you find out
你去吴淞口
in Wusong Port?
有结果吗
A batch of goods of Nakamura Naoki
里见直树有一批货
will arrive at the Shiliupu Wharf on 6th this month.
六号会到十六铺码头
He's worried about
他怕时间拖下去
further complications if delayed.
会再出麻烦
So, he wants to ship the goods
想要尽快装船
to Japan as soon as possible.
发货去日本
Tan Shiyuan promised him
谭施远答应他
to help them pass Shanghai Customs District.
从江海关想办法
The 6th.
六号
We have four days to stop the shipment of the goods
我们还有四天的时间
before the delivery date.
截停这批货
Before that,
但在此之前
I must get you well again.
我必须先让你好起来
OK.
好
The captain is still running a fever.
队长还在发烧
Well,
这样吧
I'll get a wet towel.
我去弄一条湿毛巾过来
Here you are.
来
Thank you.
谢谢
Help me out of the car.
扶我下去吧
You are weak.
你都受伤了
You need a rest.
就别折腾了
I'm feeling stifled in the car
在车里面憋得慌
and just want to step out for some fresh air.
想下去透口气
I fear I won't
我怕
have another chance
以后没机会
to do so.
再呼吸到新鲜空气了
Why did you rescue us yesterday?
昨天为什么来救我们
Do you realize the consequences?
你知道这么做的后果吗
You may never be able to r
可能从今往后
return to the precinct
你再也回不了分局
or work as a police officer again.
也再也当不了警察
I know that.
知道
Then why?
知道你还过来
You're wanted city-wide.
你现在被全城通缉
Unless the warrant is withdrawn,
通缉令一天不撤销
you'll be forced to
你就永远只能
live in constant hiding.
过这种东躲西藏的日子
Aren't you in the same position?
你不也一样
If you were me,
如果换作是你
what would you choose to do?
你会怎么选择
I don't know
我不知道自己
if I even I have a choice.
还有没有得选
But when I saw my brother was dealing
但我在吴淞口看见
with Nakamura Naoki in Wusong Port.
我哥哥跟里见直树交易
I realized that
知道了我的家人
my family is involved, too.
也参与进来
I couldn't convince myself that
我没有办法说服我自己
I have nothing to do with it.
跟这些事情没有关系
My name is Hua Zhen.
从小到大我都叫华桢
I've been proud of that
这二十多年来
my name is Hua Zhen in the past 20 years.
我一直很骄傲
I believed I
我自认为拥有
had everything I wanted
一切想要的东西
I thought that
我认为自己
every decision I'd made
做的每一个决定
was right.
都是正确的
But when I look back now,
但现在回头看
I don't think
我好像从来没有
I've ever truly known myself.
真正地认识过自己
Many people
很多人
come to the end of their lives
过完一辈子
still strangers to themselves.
对自己都很陌生
Keep doing things
坚持做
which you think right.
你认为正确的事情
That was what Mr. Deng said.
这是邓先生说的
It is Deng Mingyuan,
在我万念俱灰的时候
a CPC member,
是邓铭远先生
who lit my way
这样的共产党
with his stars when I was in despair.
用他的星光照亮了我
Weren't you also guided by him?
你不是也一样
Since I was twelve,
从我十二岁起
Mr. Deng's words have inspired me.
我就被邓先生照耀着
"Life or death,"
苟利社稷
"I will do whatever I can for the benefits of the country"
死生以之
If you understand this sentiment,
你如果能读懂这句话
you'll understand my choice.
你就会明白我的选择
These are the last words
这是邓先生
Mr. Deng left to me.
留给我的最后一句话
But now, I'm not sure
可是我不知道
if it's too late for me
自己重新选择
to choose anew.
还来不来得及
For anyone,
人只要选择对了方向
as long as the direction is correct, it is never too late.
任何时间都不晚
I want to become a person
我想成为
like Deng Mingyuan.
像邓铭远先生一样的人
We will become a person
我们必将成为
like him.
像邓铭远先生那样的人
We will.
一定会的
Take this.
拿着
Seize the moment
把握好时刻
and steer us toward survival.
带我们活下去
We'll stay alive.
我们一定会活下去的
We will.
一定
OK.
好了
You should have a rest.
你也休息会儿
It's dark outside.
天色太晚了
Can we find a way back?
我们能找到回去的路吗
Yes, we will.
会的
We must find it.
一定会找到的
Come in, please
请进
Ms. Shi,
石督察
why haven't you gone home yet?
这么晚了还没回去啊
I have some matters
我还有一些事情
to attend to.
没有处理完
We're about to turn off the power.
我们要闭电了
Do you need us to leave it on for you?
用不用给你单独留着
Please keep it on for now, thank you.
先留着吧 谢谢
OK.
好的
Recounter.
相遇
Did you sleep well?
休息得还好吗
Didn't you stay up all night long?
你一夜没睡
Let's check Chen Hao.
看看陈浩
Chen Hao.
陈浩
How's Captain?
队长怎么了
He had a bad fever.
他烧得厉害
You stay with him
要不你在这儿陪着他
and I will buy some sulfanilamide.
我去买磺胺粉
There is shrapnel left in his wound.
伤口里应该还有弹片
Sulfanilamide
磺胺粉已经
can't help anymore.
解决不了问题了
He needs a surgery immediately.
他现在需要立马手术
Then what should we do?
那我们现在怎么办
Get on the car.
上车
Is this the place
这不是彭记者
where reporter Peng works?
住的地方吗
Yes.
对
This place belongs to the NSO.
这里是救国会的地方
Feng Guangyun didn't know here.
冯广云还不知道这里
We can ask them for help.
我们可以找他们帮忙
Wait for me in the car.
你们在车里等我
OK.
好
If I see any police,
要是碰到警察或者巡捕
I'll drive around.
我就开车在周围兜圈子
Take care.
千万小心
So do you.
你也是
This is the general office of
公董局警务处
the Council.
总部办公室
I am Shi Junyu.
我是石珺昱
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
this is Xiang Yuansheng.
我是向远生
I worked as a police officer
我以前在第四警察所
in the Fourth Station House
当警察
Maybe you don't remember.
你可能不记得了
I met some trouble
我遇到了一些麻烦
I can't find another one
在上海
to ask for help
我实在找不到第二个人
in Shanghai.
可以帮忙
So, I have to call you.
所以冒昧地给你打电话
Officer Xiang,
向警官
I remember you, of course.
我当然记得你
Qiushi always mentioned you
秋实给我打电话
when she called me.
经常提起你
What happened?
出什么事了吗
A friend of mine was shot.
我一个朋友中枪了
And he needs to have a surgery now.
现在急需做手术
But I can't take him to the hospital.
但我不能带他去医院
And I can't
至于原因
tell you the reason.
我暂时也不能告诉你
I can't trust anyone else
我实在是想不到
except you.
第二个可以信任的人
Please help him.
拜托你救救他
Who is your friend?
你朋友是什么人
He's Chen Hao.
他叫陈浩
He worked as a police officer of the Fourth Station.
以前也是四所的警察
Did he hurt badly?
他受伤得严重吗
The wound isn't in the vital organ.
没有伤到要害
But it turns inflamed.
但是伤口已经开始发炎
Xiang
向警官
Chen Hao is my student
陈浩现在是
of French class.
我的法语班的学生
Even though I didn't know you,
就算我不认识你
I'd help him.
我也会帮他的
Thank you.
谢谢你
What should I do?
我该怎么做
Drive him to the Shengen Book Store
往长乐路三号的
in No. 3, Changle Road.
圣恩书店开
Come in, please.
请进
Ready? We need to go.
准备好了吗 该出发了
Did the director start off?
总监已经出发了吗
Yes.
对
Nobody is allowed to be absent in this meeting.
今天开会不能有人缺席
Give me 5 minutes on the way.
路上耽误五分钟
I have to get a dress
我到裁缝铺
in the tailor's shop.
取件衣服就走
Let's go.
走吧
It's on the way, after all.
反正顺路
Mrs. Wang,
王太太
why are you doing the job yourself?
自己在忙啊
Where's Mr. Wang?
王先生呢
Why doesn't he help you?
也没出来帮你
He's gone to purchase goods.
他进货去了
A newsstand is opened
我看你们店铺门口
besides your store.
新开了一个杂志摊
He moved here few days before.
这两天刚来的
But,
不过
he doesn't look like a businessperson.
不像会做生意的
It doesn't matter.
那也没关系
The more stores in our street
反正咱们这个街
the better.
越热闹越好
Indeed.
也是
I got client, Mrs. Wang.
王太太 我客人来了
I'll go back now.
我先回去了
OK.
好
Mrs. Ji.
季太太
Ms. Shi, welcome.
石小姐 你们来了
Follow me.
先到那面去
OK.
好
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
Help yourself, please.
你们先随便看一看
I'll fetch the dress.
你先去取衣服
OK.
好的
Mrs. Ji,
季太太
this is my bill.
这是我的取货单
Follow me please.
您跟我进来
I've fixed the cheongsam
上次那件旗袍
according to your figure
我按照你的尺寸
and I've tightened the cuff.
把袖口又收紧了一点
Please check.
你看看合不合适
OK.
好
Here.
来
The cuff looks suitable this time.
这次袖子看着差不多了
After Wei Daiqing left last time,
上次魏岱擎走了之后
there're always people
门口就一直有人
looking out near my shop.
守在这儿
It must be his subordinates.
应该是他的人
Be careful when you go.
你出门的时候一定小心
I've got the information that
我通过公董局
the one who is behind the investigation
查到调查安全房的人
is Wei Daiqing.
就是魏岱擎
I have contact with
已经联系到
Chen Hao and Xiang Yuansheng.
陈浩和向远生了
Chen Hao was shot
陈浩中枪了
and he needs an immediate surgery.
需要马上做手术
This is sulfanilamide.
这是磺胺粉
I've told Xiang Yuansheng
我已经让向远生
to take him to the Shengen Book Store.
带他去圣恩书店了
OK.
行
I'll go there right away.
我马上赶过去
What about the people spying on you?
外面怎么办
I can handle it.
我能处理
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
How do you like
你觉得这旗袍的长度
the length of the cheongsam?
怎么样
I think it is a little longer.
我感觉还是长了一些
It may need a trim.
要不要修剪一下
I'll fix it then.
那我再帮你改一下
Thank you.
谢谢
Junyu, we must hurry up.
珺昱 我们得快点
Let's go.
走吧
Take care.
当心
So do you.
你也是
Rubbish collection.
收垃圾了
I haven't seen you before.
我看你脸生
Are you new here?
新来的吧
Yes.
对
I've just moved in
刚来几天
and started a small business.
做点儿小生意
This is my shop.
我是这家铺子的
We can help each other.
以后相互多照应着
Sure.
好
I'll take out the trash.
我去倒垃圾
Could you please mind the store for me?
你帮我看着点铺子
If there is a visitor,
如果有人来
just tell him I'll be back soon.
就说我马上就回来
This shop, please.
就是这家铺子
OK.
行 行 行
Thank you.
麻烦了
Rubbish collection.
倒垃圾